i grew my very first plant when i was
about six years old
i took a sunflower seed from my mother's
bird feeder and planted it in a cup
several weeks later it bloomed and a
lifetime love of flowers flourished
along with it
[Music]
growing up i did much of my schooling at
home my mother noticed i love to read
and write and that i had trouble
concentrating in loud environments
she encouraged me to pursue my passions
at home to my heart's contentment
every few months we'd receive a box full
of our homework for the semester
it consisted of our curriculum as well
as a dozen books on all topics
ranging from biology history and
folklore
i remember first reading anne of green
gables at 11 fascinated by this
incredible heroine who was absolutely
enraptured by her natural world
and had more confidence in her little
finger than my insecure self had in
their entire being
intrigued i continued on to read the
story of laura ingalls
calpurnia tate and eventually turned to
biographies on jane goodall and beatrix
potter
i devoured these books and promptly
decided that i would be the world's next
great naturalist things didn't quite
work out that way
but these women didn't still within me
the sight
an ability to magnify one's own gaze to
soak in
every little detail of life itself
[Music]
armed with a microscope in a nature
journal full of rushed sketches
my child self would walk out my door
into a wooded area near my home
and collect samples of everything i
could find
a mushroom a tiny piece of moss a seed
under a microscope they bloomed into
tiniest civilizations full of intricate
detail and potential
i would write down my scientific
observations completely misusing biology
terms
and sprinkling latin words here and
there for posterity
the end result was a quite nonsensical
nature journal
that would have made the likes of mr
audubon raise an eyebrow
[Music]
over a decade later i've reclaimed that
curiosity and love of plants and flowers
while i do proper research now in order
to not inadvertently kill
everything i try to grow i purposefully
leave some knowledge gaps open for
experimentation
i could read all about how to grow the
perfect sunflower down to an exact
science
or i could find out myself by taking
notes and making observations
i like to take that approach and imagine
myself as a student
of the plants i grow they have a lot to
teach me
i think if i remember to listen
gardening requires patience
and slowness curiosity and often problem
solving
you can be a gardener whether you grow a
single flower in a pot
or an entire field full of vegetables
whether you know what you're doing or
not
maybe you're like me and like to walk
the line
i have not lived here long enough to
have a developed cottage garden
it is still in its infancy through trial
and error i am learning to accommodate
an environment that is dry
and hot and rather brutal to delicate
blooms
i'm fascinated by the fact that even in
the driest of grasslands
where only sage and bunch grass are
abundant even the most delicate of
flowers can be cultivated
if given enough loving care i remember
that if i ever feel lost
in my story renewal takes time but it's
always possible
[Music]
i wanted to thank all of you for your
lovely
messages and words of affirmation in my
last video
it meant so much and
i'm feeling so much better there's such
an amazing
power in just taking a respite and
sleeping well and eating well and
i just feel like a new person so i i
really appreciate
all your advice and insight and
i felt quite connected to all of you
from reading
all your lovely words as you probably
know
my favorite season is spring the
wildflower season is just breathtaking
and i've never been anywhere where the
flowers are so vibrant
and so abundant and i'm so excited to
share that with you
the overall goal with this garden is to
be a 100 edible
flower and herb garden so we'll see how
that goes it comes with its own
set of challenges because i have a
rabbit
that likes to eat everything so
i'm very excited to bring you on the
journey of growing the garden i think
this year
hopefully it will be very abundant
unless darcy escapes from his cage and
eats
everything so but that may happen and if
that happens
we'll just have a little memorial for
all the plants and
we'll move on
you